ANANDRAJ RAJENDRAN

Professional II-Product, System & PLM Engineer

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Frontend Team Lead with 7+ years of experience developing applications with high capabilities. An individual with a keen interest in, Angular, JavaScript, Node JS, HTML, CSS, Flutter possessing good interpersonal and analytical skills, who wish to use technical knowledge catering to the needs of the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

March 2022 – Present | Capgemini Engineering, Bangalore, IN FRONTEND TEA

- Involved in sprint planning, effort estimation, team integration, design discussion, team management, performance improvement, security.
- Developing code and distributed work to maximize time and hit KPIs, build customer relationships.
- Supervised, reviewed, and coached client-service representatives who consistently exceeded business goals.
- Documented the design and Collected customer feedback and implemented procedural changes.

May 2019 – March 2022 | Accenture, Bangalore, IN

AI ENGINEEERING SENIOR ANALYST

- Developed a mobile app with flutter, built android and iOS apps using which various features like notifications, chatbots etc. were implemented.
- Created Digital Assistant chatbots for Cognitive Insurance Platform which
 is connected to AWS LEX. It includes features like sharing photos for
 image processing, reactive forms for motor insurance and home insurance.
- Created journey screens with D3 js where we can connect between the components in EB Application, Screen for rules in recipes, state management and other enhancement activities in EB Application.

June 2016 – May 2019 | Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai, IN PROGRAMMER SENIOR ANALYST

- Created various B2C sites for countries like Hong Kong, United States, China etc.
- Designed and developed a supply chain animated flow screen.
- Involved in sprint planning, estimations, team management and client interactions.

- (+91) 9677235535
- mailanandroid@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/anandrajrajendran-554151103

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Angular
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- HTML
- CSS
- Node IS
- Flutter

EDUCATION

B. TECH / IT RMK Engineering College, Chennai 2012 - 2016

AWARDS

- WOW award winner, 2023.
- Best Trainer of the Year, 2018
- K-C Hackathon, Second prize winner.
- Best UI developer of the Year,
 2019